What we want to talk about right now is the importance of our defensive backs and coming up to stop the run play.
Obviously, the main thing to the 6-2 defense is we want to stop the run.
We believe that this team offensively is going to run the ball the majority of the time and we don't have to worry a whole lot about the pass.
But the first responsibility of this guy has got to be don't get burnt on the pass play.
So first of all when the ball is snapped, he has got to start his back peddle.
He's got to pick up the quarterback.
He's got to find out if the quarterback handed the ball off or if he's dropping back so that he has to go into pass coverage.
Once he recognizes that that guy has handed the ball off, he has to first of all get this guy off of him who's going to be coming out to block him.
He's got to stay low, get into him, shed the block. And then he's got to come up as hard as he can.
Once he gets up to the line of scrimmage and he can get involved in the play, he's either got to do one of two things.
Break down and float in and make the open field tackle. Or two he may have to come in and help a team mate out.
And maybe get a strip, cause a fumble and finish out the play.
So its very important for our defensive backs to be able to read, shed block, come up and make tackles.
Now our safety that's back, he's probably not going to make a whole lot of tackles in the run game, but he still has to try to find the ball, come up and try to help out.